DANIEL SHAW

JUNIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER



✓ danielshaw71@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-shaw-ds98/



PROFILE

Over the past year I have started my coding training to follow my career ambition of becoming a Fullstack Developer. This began through Codeacademy supplemented by Free Code Camp and Youtube, and since October I joined Le Wagon Web Development Course and have graduated as a Fullstack Developer. I worked 2 jobs part-time throughout spring and summer to help fund the course, whilst continuing to learn to code.

SKILLS

- Strong interpersonal and customer service skills
- Team leadership and management capabilities.
- Problem solving
- Constructed my own computer from self taught learning
- Microsoft Applications

COURSES

LE WAGON | 2023

- 9-week full-time intensive web development bootcamp, accredited by BCS
- Learned and used HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, SQL, Git, Github, Figma, Heroku and Ruby/Ruby on Rails
- Conceptual learning included OOP, MVC, APIs and Version Control

CODECADEMY | 2023

Languages learnt: Javascript,
 Ruby, CSS & HTML

EDUCATION

UWE UNIVERSITY 2018

BUISNESS ENTREPREURSHIP Completed year 1 achieving a 2.1 Received ILM: Level 3 Award in Leadership & Management.

EMANUEL SCHOOL 2016

A-LEVELS: Mathematics, Economics, Business Studies & Geography

PROJECTS

VLOYAL

Pitched an idea for a web app called 'VLoyal' and completed the project within 2 weeks in a team of 5. VLoyal was created to turn paper loyalty cards into virtual loyalty cards storing them in one app, using a QR code scanner to add virtual stamps.

- Acted as the project lead and project manager.
- Managed all merges and resolved all conflicts in Github.
- Implemented the QR code scanning feature to the web app.
- Worked on multiple animations using Javascript.
- Used Figma and CSS to add styling throughout the web app.
- Presented and showcased the final product to 100+ people.

SUPPER CLUB

Designed, implemented and shipped to production a clone of AirBnB called 'Supper Club'. The web app was for users to create and showcase their supper club events, as well as to discover and buy tickets to other supper clubs. Lead and managed this week long project.

EXPERIENCE

DESIGN MY NIGHT | VENUE FINDING | 2022 - 2023

Demonstrated clear effective communication and consistent fast response times, operating as the intermediary between clients and venues. I converted 12 sales within 8 weeks.

Attended multiple networking events, developing client management and networking skills.

FORTEM INTERNATIONAL | EVENTS SALES MANAGER | 2022

Held a client-facing role researching and connecting with new businesses to build a portfolio of clients for global trade shows run by Fortem International. Developed skills in sales, business development and client relationship management.

IDEAL LAND | PROPERTY & LAND AGENT | 2019 - 2021

Bought in £7M worth of property deals between 2020-2021. Managed the office and day to day business, including setting up and updating the website, and building the Company LinkedIn profile from 200 to 1,300 followers within a year. My responsibilities included;

- Leading searches for land and properties, monitoring and updating the databases.
- Drawing up contracts for deals including NDA's, Retention letters and Heads of Terms.
- Building relationships with new and current clients, as well as networking with industry professionals.
- Arranging GDPR and AML training for the company and managing the continued use of these practices.